[Evans] Here's one way to define sum_list.
这是定义 sum_list 的一种方法
It's a procedure that takes in 1 input,
这个方法需要有一个输入参数
and we'll name the input p as the name for our parameter.
我们将把这个输入命名为 p 作为我们参数的名字
I tend to use p as the name for a list. There's no really good reason for that.
我倾向于使用 p 来作列表的名字 这不是硬性规定
I don't want to use the letter l because l looks too much like a 1.
我之所以不用字母 l 是因为 l 看起来很像数字1
I don't want to use m, n, or o because m and n are used usually to represent numbers
之所以不用 m n 或 o 是因为 m 和 n 往往被用来代表数字
and o looks too much like a 0.
而 o 看起来很像数字0
So the first good letter to use after l is p.
这样 字母 l 之后第一个合适的字母就是 p
Of course you could use any name you want for your parameter name.
当然 你可以使用任何名字给你的参数命名
To define sum_list we're going to introduce a variable to keep track of the sum so far.
为定义 sum_list 我们将引入一个变量来追踪目前的和
Let's call that result.
我们把这称为 result (结果)
Initially, the value of the result of 0.
最初 result 的值为0
Next we'll use a for-loop to go through the elements.
接下来 我们将使用一个 for 循环来遍历各元素
We're going to go through the elements of p.
我们将遍历 p 中的各元素
Each time we execute the block of the for-loop
每次我们执行 for 循环中的程序块
the value of e will be the current element of p,
e 的值将是 p 的当前元素
and we'll go through the loop once for each element of p in order.
我们将在这个循环中依次使用 p 中每一个元素
So what we want to do is add that value to result.
我们要把这个值与结果相加
When we then get to the for-loop, that means we've gone through all the elements
当我们完成了 for 循环 这意味着我们遍历了每个元素
and we should return the result.
那么我们应当返回 result
Let's try this in the Python interpreter.
我们在 Python 解释器中试一试
We've defined sum_list.
我们已经定义了 sum_list
Let's try running it.
现在尝试运行它
We do get the value 12.
我们得到的值果然是12
What do you think would happen if we run sum_list like this,
如果我们这样运行 sum_list 传入一个空的列表
passing in the empty list?
会出现什么情况？
The answer is that we get the value 0,
答案是 得到的值为0
which is what we expect, right?
正是我们预料的结果 对吧
The sum of no elements is 0.
当没有元素时 和便为0
And if we look at the code, that's exactly what happens.
我们看看代码 情况完全一致
Initially, we set the result to 0.
最初 我们设定结果为0
The for-loop goes through all the elements of p,
for 循环遍历 p 中所有元素
but if there are no elements of p, it doesn't execute at all.
但如果 p 中无元素 那么循环便不会执行
And so we go to the next statement, which returns the result, which has the value 0.
所以 我们去到下一个语句 即返回 result result 的值为0